Once upon a time in London, there lived
four siblings, Peter, Susan, Edmund and Lucy Pavensey.
During World War II, London was not
a very safe place, so the
children from Pavensey had to go to the peasant.
They were with an old professor.
I lived alone and it was a little strange, but
He liked children.
His house was also a rather strange place.
I was in the middle of a forest.
Inside the house there were many stairs, large
rooms and bedrooms.
On the first day of their stay, the
children decided to explore the house.
They passed through different rooms full of books, pictures
and all sorts of things.
Finally, they arrived at an almost empty room.
I had nothing except a huge old locker room.
There's nothing interesting here, said Peter.
After that, everyone left the
room, except Lucy.
She opened the locker room and went inside.
It had to look like the locker room was more
bigger than it seemed.
There were several stairs full of shoes there.
So Lucy went deeper into the
locker room.
She hoped to reach the wall soon.
She walked up many stairs full of shoes.
Suddenly, he felt something cold on his face.
She looked up and saw the snow falling
from the sky.
Lucy was standing in the middle of a forest
greenhouse.
She was scared and excited at the same time.
She looked back and saw the locker room
among the trees.
I can always come back if something happens, she thought.
And he continued.
After a while, she saw a lamp
on the street.
Why is there a lamp on the street?
in the middle of a forest?
she asked.
She stood there, thinking about what to do.
continuation.
Suddenly, a strange person appeared from behind
of the trees.
It looked like a human, but it had legs.
of cat.
Creatures like these are called faunas.
The fauna had a lamp on his head
with one hand and several mouths with the
other.
He had hair and little hair, and he had two
small eyes on his head.
When he saw Lucy, he got scared and left
their mouths.
Oh my God!
cry.
Good night!
he said politically to Lucy.
replied the fauna.
May I ask if you are a human girl?
Of course I am!
Lucy said, surprised.
I just wanted to be sure!
I've never seen human girls or boys before!
explained the fauna.
Then he introduced himself.
My name is Tumnus!
Good to meet you, Mr. Tumnus!
My name is Lucy!
How did you get to Narnia, Lucy?
Lucy didn't quite understand.
Where did you end up?
asked.
Narnia is the name of this place!
said Tumnus.
Oh, I understand!
I came from a locker room, Lucy replied.
Locker room?
I don't like geography!
I don't know this country!
said Tumnus.
You don't have a bed!
Don't you feel cold?
May I offer you a cup of tea?
Yes, if it doesn't take too long!
Lucy added.
The place of Tumnus was very nice.
After tea, he took a strange musical instrument
and began to play a silent song.
Lucy liked it, but she felt sleepy.
She asked Tumnus to let her go.
At home.
It's too late now!
said Tumnus, suddenly starting to cry.
Because?
Lucy didn't understand what was happening.
He put his arms around the fauna.
What's happening?
he asked softly.
When Tumnus could speak again, he explained to him
all.
A terrible hero called the White Hero ruled
Narnia.
Because of him, there was always winter in the
country, but there was never Christmas.
Following his order, I have to catch any
human to enter Narnia and bring them to
her, Tumnus explained.
I don't know what he does with them.
Maybe they'll kill them.
But you'll let me, right?
Lucy asked.
Tumnus was afraid of the hero, but also
Lucy liked him.
He didn't want her to die, so he remembered
to take her back to the lamp
the street.
Lucy entered the locker room and soon returned
to the professor's house.
He left the locker room and saw his
brothers and sister.
Lucy told them about her adventures, but they didn't
they believed them.
This can't be, said Peter.
You spent less than a minute in the locker room.
Edmund was especially mean to Lucy.
You are neither stupid nor crazy, he told him.
So Lucy stopped talking about Narnia,
but she was very miserable.
Several days passed.
One night the children were playing hide and seek.
look for.
Lucy went to the empty room and
he hid in the locker room.
Edmund saw her and followed her.
He called her, but Lucy didn't answer.
While searching for Lucy in the darkness, he saw
a light and headed towards it, but
To his surprise he soon found himself in the middle
from a greenhouse forest.
He remembered Lucy's story and felt
bad for his behavior.
What if it were true?
Suddenly, Edmund saw a large squadron
carried by a reindeer.
A beautiful woman sat in the squadron.
He wore white clothes and his face was also
white, cold and serious.
The squad stopped and the woman
spoke to Edmund.
What are you?
My name is Edmund, he said.
The woman became very angry.
How do you talk to the queen of Narnia?
shout.
I'm sorry, I didn't know you were a queen, he replied.
Edmund.
I'm not from here.
Well, where are you from?
asked.
Are you a human child?
I am, yes.
I came here through a door of
locker room.
Please, it doesn't hurt.
The queen looked at him for a while.
Then suddenly he spoke to her in a way
much more pleasant.
Poor child, you're probably cold, he said in a
soft voice.
Come sit in my squad, and I'll cover you.
with my clothes.
Edmund did not like this idea, but
He was moving from the cold, so he went up to the squadron.
The queen put her clothes around him,
then gave him an unusual hot drink and
a little cinnamon.
Cinnamon became delicious.
Once Edmund started eating it, he didn't
could stop.
As they ran, the queen asked her questions.
She learned about her siblings and about the
Lucy's adventure with Tumnus.
When Edmund finished the box of cinnamon, he
asked for more.
However, the queen did not give him any more.
sweets.
I'll only give you more if you bring your
brother and sisters here, she said.
You are a smart kid.
You like me, and I don't have children.
I can turn you into the prince of Narnia.
You will live in a palace among these mountains, he said
she, showing him two mountains in the distance.
You will come with a golden chrono and you will eat
cinnamon all day.
But before that, I want to see your
siblings.
Don't tell them anything about me.
Let it be a surprise.
Edmund was ready to do anything, just
to taste the sweets once more.
It was like a drug to him now.
He promised the queen that he would do the
to ask him.
The queen left Edmund and disappeared.
On his way back, he met Lucy.
I was glad to see him in Narnia.
He told her about Tumnus and the white nun,
who was not a real queen, already
everyone hated them.
Edmund realized that the nun
dangerous and the white woman were the same
person.
It made him feel sick.
Now he was scared for his life.
But he also really wanted to eat the candy
again.
So he said nothing.
Lucy was excited to tell Susan and
to Peter another story about Narnia.
She was sure that Edmund would support her.
now.
However, when Peter and Susan asked him
to Edmund about this, he said, Lucy and
I was just playing a game.
She made it all up.
These words really bothered Lucy, and
she left the room.
Peter was angry.
He told Edmund to stop being
so horrible to her sister.
Shocked by Lucy, Susan and Peter turned around
to the professor to give his advice.
Why do you think his story is not
TRUE?
asked the teacher.
Had he lied before?
Never.
Well, so far.
This story of the nun and the forest
It can't be true, Peter replied.
We're afraid it's crazy, he said.
Susan.
Take a look at her.
Talk to her.
And you will see that it is not out of its
mind, the teacher told them.
If she's not lying, and if not
It's crazy, then his story is true.
But I didn't have time to go back and forth,
Susan shouted.
It only took a few seconds.
If it's a different world, its time is too.
It could be different, the professor replied.
Do you really think there are other worlds?
Peter asked, surprised.
They could be right around, the professor replied.
For a while after that, everything went well.
Lucy didn't mention the shirt again, and
Edmund stopped laughing.
But the peace did not last long.
One day, some visitors came to the house
of the teacher.
The children did not want to meet them, so they
hid in the shirt.
Susan turned and immediately saw the woods
snow-capped mountains.
They were in Narnia.
Lucy was excited.
Finally I could show them this wonderful new world.
Lucy wanted everyone to meet Mr.
Tumnus, so he took them to his house.
However, the children found the little house
completely destroyed.
The door broke and snow covered
the floor.
Peter found a note that said Tumnus the
Fawn was taken by the secret police for
crimes against the Queen of Narnia.
Lucy was very worried.
She wanted to find Mr. Tumnus and save
him.
Edmund wanted to go back, but Susan and
Peter were on Lucy's side.
However, they had no idea how to find
the fawn.
All of a sudden, Lucy saw a bright
red bird.
I wish this bird could show us where
Mr. Tumnus is, she said.
She took a step forward.
Immediately the bird flew off the tree and
landed on the next one, then looked at
the children and waited.
Lucy, Susan and Peter decided they should follow
the bird.
Edmund was unsure if the bird was a
good sign or a bad sign.
He also remembered the Queen's promises and did
not want to go against her.
The children went through the forest, the bird
showing them the way.
Then suddenly the bird disappeared from view.
They stood there, looking around and trying to
decide what to do next.
At that moment a beaver appeared in the
distance.
The beaver looked at the children and made
signs for them to come closer.
They came up to him and started talking.
It turned out that his name was Mr.
Beaver and he was Mr. Tumnus's friend.
Tumnus felt that he was in danger, Mr.
Beaver said.
He told me to meet you and take
you to ...
He stopped and then said very quietly, Aslan.
Although none of the children knew Aslan, they
all reacted to that name.
Susan, Peter and Lucy all felt happy and
excited.
Edmund, however, felt scared for no particular reason.
And where is Mr. Tumnus?
Lucy asked.
Shh!
Not here.
We need to go to a safer place.
The trees are listening, and they can tell
her about us, Mr. Beaver said.
Then he asked the children to follow him.
On their way Edmund saw a small river.
It ran down the valley toward two small
hills.
Those are the hills that the queen told
me about, he thought to himself.
Her palace is right there.
Edmund remembered the candy and the queen's promise
to make him a prince.
Suddenly he felt like running away to join
her at the palace.
But when the children reached the beaver's house,
Edmund went in with everybody else.
They had a very nice dinner with Mr.
Beaver and his wife, Mrs. Beaver.
They all wanted an explanation of what was
going on.
So after dinner Mr. Beaver told them everything.
Mr. Tumnus was really taken by the secret
police, and it is bad news, he began.
People don't know exactly what the witch does
to criminals, but I am afraid that...
I am afraid that she turns them into
stone.
Can we do something to help?
Lucy cried.
It is an awful situation, and it is
all happening because he saved me.
Well, you cannot enter the witch's palace and
come out alive, Mr. Beaver replied.
I suppose only Aslan could help us.
Who is Aslan?
Tell us about him, several voices said at
the same time.
Suddenly that strange, exciting feeling came over the
children again.
Don't you know?
Aslan is the king of Narnia, a real
one, but he doesn't visit the land often.
I haven't ever seen him, for example, but
he should soon come to fight the witch.
Won't she turn him into stone too?
Edmund asked.
Lion?
No, I don't think she's strong enough to
even look him in the eye, Mr. Beaver
replied.
He will win, and it will be spring
again.
Will we see him?
Susan asked.
This is why you are here, human girl,
Mr. Beaver told her.
According to an ancient legend, four human kings
and queens will someday take the throne.
Then the land will be free and happy.
You four are the first people in Narnia,
so I think the legend is about you.
But isn't Aslan a man, Peter asked?
And what about the witch?
Aslan is a lion, the king of all
animals, and the witch would like to be
human, but she actually isn't, the beaver explained.
The children were a little scared of meeting
a lion, but Mr. Beaver told them that
Aslan was very kind.
They were going to meet Aslan the following
day, in a place called the Stone Table.
Everyone paid close attention to what Beaver was
saying, and they missed one important thing.
Lucy noticed it first.
Wait, where is Edmund?
she asked.
Everyone grew worried.
They ran outside, shouted his name and searched
for him, almost falling through the soft, deep
snow.
But there was no answer.
They came back to the beaver's house, tired.
Peter wanted to go search for Edmund again,
but Mr. Beaver did not support that idea.
He joined the white witch.
He is on her side now, he said.
Edmund is a traitor.
I saw it in his eyes when he
entered.
But we cannot go to the witch's palace
now.
Why not?
Lucy asked.
She will turn all four of you into
stone, and she will rule over Narnia forever,
he replied.
But she won't touch Edmund just yet.
She knows that you will come to save
him.
So first you need to talk to Aslan,
and he will tell you what to do.
Now we need to run fast.
If the white witch finds us here, she
will kill us.
And so they all set off immediately.
After a long, hard journey, Edmund reached the
witch's palace, which was a small castle with
many little, sharp towers.
It looked scary, but he could not turn
back.
The palace had a garden, and Edmund entered
it.
He saw many stone figures there.
One of them was a huge lion, and
Edmund got scared at first.
He thought that the animal was real.
When he realized that it was a figure,
he laughed.
Maybe it is Aslan.
The queen has turned him into stone, and
he will never be the king of Narnia
again, he thought.
On the other side of the garden, stone
steps led to a door.
On the stairs lay a big wolf.
This time it was a real animal, not
a stone figure.
It was Mogrim, the leader of the secret
police.
The wolf allowed Edmund to enter, and took
him to the queen.
They went through a long, dark hall with
many stone figures along the walls.
The queen saw that Edmund came alone, and
became very angry.
Edmund grew so scared that he told her
everything about Beaver and Aslan.
When the witch heard Aslan's name, she could
not believe it at first.
Then she called a servant and said, Get
the sled ready, and don't put any bells
on it.
Meanwhile, the beavers and the pavenzis walked through
the forest.
They traveled for a long time and finally
found a place to rest.
It was a big, dry hole in the
ground.
The children went in and fell asleep immediately.
The sound of bells woke them up.
They thought it might be the witch, and
Mr. Beaver went outside to check.
Soon the children heard his voice saying, No
need to worry, come here.
None of them expected to see Santa Claus,
but it was him.
The witch kept me locked for a long
time, but I am here at last, he
said.
Aslan is on his way, and she is
getting weaker.
Then Santa gave presents to everybody.
Although the children usually got toys, this time
they got useful tools.
Peter received a sword and a silver shield.
Susan received a bow with arrows and a
small horn.
Santa did not want her to fight, so
he told her to only use the bow
when absolutely necessary.
If in danger, she could blow the horn
to call for help.
Lucy received a knife and a bottle of
medicine that could help with any injury or
illness.
Can I fight with this knife?
Lucy asked.
I am strong enough.
Only use it to protect yourself, my dear.
It is awful when women have to fight,
Santa told her.
And now, have some food and tea.
Merry Christmas and good luck!
Santa gave them all hope, so they were
soon ready to continue their difficult trip.
6.
At the same moment, Edmund was not having
a great time with the witch.
She was rude to him and did not
give him any sweets.
Upon hearing the news, she ordered Magrim to
go and kill the beavers and the children.
Then she sat on the sled with Edmund,
and they rode to the stone table.
On their way, they passed a group of
animals.
The animals were eating Christmas food.
Where did you get that?
she asked.
Santa Claus gave it to us, the poor
animals replied.
The angry witch immediately turned them into stone.
Edmund was very scared.
He really wanted to go back to his
siblings and be friends with them again.
But it was too late.
He was wet and cold because he had
no coat, and he was very sad, too.
The snow slowly became wetter and not very
thick anymore.
The ground was soft, and it was hard
for the sled to go on.
Then the snow started turning into water.
Finally, the sled stopped completely.
The witch, her servant and Edmund got out
of the sled and continued on foot.
As they walked, grass grew around them, bright
flowers pushed out of the ground, and black
trees turned green.
Happy little rivers ran down the hill, and
suddenly birds started to sing.
The sky was clear and blue.
Spring was finally here.
The birds and the pavenzes were happy to
see spring coming.
They knew they could now fight the witch.
and win, because only winter gave them
can.
When they arrived at the stone table, Aslan
it was already there.
He was beautiful and amazing at the same time.
His clothes were bright as gold, and the
children were amazed with fear and admiration.
Peter accompanied him first, and Aslan accompanied him
and the other children.
Then he asked him, Where is the room?
He left us and joined the witch
white, Peter replied.
I think it happened because of me.
It was not pleasant to Edmund.
Can we still save him?
We can, Aslan replied.
But it won't be easy.
In the distance, Peter could see a palace
on the sea coast, bright as a
star.
It was Caer Paraval, the place where the Pavenzes
were going to be kings and queens.
Suddenly, Peter heard a loud sound.
It was Susan's hat.
I was in danger.
Peter ran to help her and saw a pity
scene.
Susan climbed a tall tree, and a
huge grey animal was trying to lure her.
It was Magrim.
Susan couldn't reach the top of the tree,
and the hat was very close.
Peter felt sick, but he needed to do something.
He tried to reach the cap with his sword,
and lost it for the first time.
Then he went ahead and managed to put the sword
right in the heart of the animal.
For a moment, the hat was calm.
Then he fell down dead.
Susan ran to Peter and they hugged each other.
Then Aslan called Peter and asked him
to rise to his feet.